Now, this is going to be a quick lecture on Amazon bedrock automated reasoning so Amazon
bedrock automated reasoning checks help improve factual accuracy of the large language model
responses.
So, in summary, bedrock automated reasoning helps reduce hallucinations within the large
language model responses.
Automated reasoning checks is part of the Amazon bedrock guardrails.
Now how does it work?
So, through logic based algorithms and mathematical validation automated reasoning checks
validate LLM output against domain knowledge encoded in the automated reasoning policy
to help prevent factual inaccuracies.
Now, that is a lot of complicated words.
Can now let us try and understand this through an example on how Amazon bedrock automated
reasoning works.
Now, let us say you have built a generative A application which allows your customers to
file home insurance claims through a chatbot driven by a large language model.
Now, you have this generative A application here and customer asks which documents are required
to file home insurance claim.
Now, what this generative A application most likely is going to do is it is going to
refer to a document that is stored in backend may be a PDF document in S3 bucket.
So, it is going to refer to the document and return response to the customer question.
Now, there could be some scenarios where it hallucinates and to reduce that what you can
do is you can introduce bedrock automated reasoning.
And if you do that what you need to do first let us say you have this home insurance policy
document.
So, you are going to upload that home insurance policy document and once you upload the
document and enable automated reasoning checks it is going to extract rules from this home
insurance policy document and you can see here automated reasoning policy.
So, what do these rules look like and if we refer this question let us say if you have to
file home insurance claim then maybe you need to attach the policy ID maybe driving license
and few other documents.
So, it will extract all these rules and then what you can also do is you can have your
subject matter expert look at the rules that have been extracted and then refine them based
on your requirements.
Now, once these rules have been created let us understand how it is going to reduce hallucination.
Now, to our same question which documents are required to file home insurance claim let
say our large language model that is driving the generative applications says to file the
insurance claim you need policy ID driving license and maybe it hallucinates and says
the third thing that is required is your income proof.
So, since our bedrock automated reasoning is part of the Amazon bedrock guardrails it is
going to validate the foundation model response where it had said three documents with
these rules that have been extracted by the automated reasoning checks.
So, it will see that only two documents are required policy ID and driving license and
you do not require the income document.
So, that is how it can reduce hallucination within the generative A applications.
Okay, so that's pretty much it from this lecture as in the next lecture. Thank you.